<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello, World! on The Electrical Engineer&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello, World! on The Electrical Engineer&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>The Electrical Engineer  2018 -</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(On- Going) Project 3: Stock Analyzer using Shiny</title>
      <link>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>This project is under construction! Idea: Front -&amp;gt; Back Dev -&amp;gt; Deploy Things to learn:  Shiny mongoDB Amazon EC2 Docker javaScript and others &amp;hellip;  Kindly drop me an email if there are any skills I need to acquire.
I would be extremely grateful.
 Thank you, have a nice day ahead of you! =) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specialization: Time Series Analysis and its Models (Classic, Machine, Deep)</title>
      <link>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Time is gold. It is our most valuable asset.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Thus, understanding things that involves time will be rewarding, may be as a person or as a business man.&amp;quot;
In this post, I will be sharing my two years of search about Time Series, and how we must deal with it.
First, let us define Time Series.
According to Investopedia.com, &amp;ldquo;A time series is a sequence of data points that occur in successive order over some period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Forecasting Competition  </title>
      <link>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/review/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Forecasting is not fortune telling. It is a scientific and mathematical approach to give businesses insights of what might happen in the future i.e. trends and seasonality. However, it is never accurate yet it is useful.&amp;quot;
Nowadays, many businesses lose money and understanding the why it happenned and when will it happen is crucial in mitigating the continuous downtrend of the business status.
Today, I am going to give you a glimpse on how forecasting is being done for the past 7 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Seeing into the Future</title>
      <link>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Hi! It&amp;rsquo;s my birthday today. Thank you for passing by! Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s start seeing my future!
 Nah! I’m just fooling around.
Now, let us become serious, here is an approach to a financial time series data.
What to expect in project?
In this project, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to analyze the effect of events when in a weekly transaction dataset. Expect visualizations that involves:
1. Autocorrelations and PACF 2. Transformations (Log and Standard) 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Product Pricing Prediction Algorithm with XGBoost</title>
      <link>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement
The R&amp;amp;D department needs assistance in coming up with new product concepts and pricing based on the current product line.
Solution Summary
The following are some of the product gaps we’ve found in the current line of products.
 Aluminum Over Mountain Aluminum Triathalon  To estimate the price of new bicycle models based on the current fleet. A pricing model using predictive analytics is developed. This keeps the price of new models in line with those of similar models in the marketplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Customer Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement: A marketing department wishes to boost email campaign engagement by grouping or segmenting customers based on their purchasing behaviors.
Solution Summary Four distinct customer segments have been identified using K-means clustering and UMAP 2D Projection. The four customer segments were described using the customer’s most recent product purchases.
 Segment 1 Preferences: Road Bikes, Below $3200 (Economical Models) Segment 2 Preferences: Mountain Bikes, Above $3200 (Premium Models) Segment 3 Preferences: Road Bikes, Above $3200 (Premium Models) Segment 4 Preferences: Both Road and Mountain, Below $3200 (Economical Models)  Customer Preferences</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact me</title>
      <link>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theElectricalengineersblog.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>   Site Link     Facebook : https://www.facebook.com/engr.jvilltolentino   Twitter : https://twitter.com/jvilltolentino   Github : https://github.com/jvilltolentino   LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/jvilltolentino    If you have any queries on how I did any of the projects, hit me up by sending an email.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
